Oh man! This feels like a real adventure!
天啊 真像在冒险呢
I thought so at first.
会这么想也只有一开始
Just when will we reach the place?
到底有多远啊
We've been walking on the mountains for three days!
我们已经在山里整整三天了
Just a little bit more. We're almost there.
没多远 就快到了
Really?
真的吗
Stay on your toes.
但是不能大意哦
That'd be you if you ever fell off the cliff.
要是不小心掉下去 就会变那样
Those bones are massive!
好大的骨头
Great Sage, what are those creatures?
贤者大人 那是什么
Probably monsters from the Abyss King's era.
恐怕是深渊王时代的魔物
A fierce battle once took place
因为大山壁卡欧戈米卡
in the Kaogamika Mountains.
曾经发生过激烈的战斗
I never knew monsters of this size existed!
原来有这么大的魔物存在过
This is amazing!
好厉害
Why did she get so excited?
为什么她这么有精神啊
Thanks for scouting ahead.
侦察辛苦你了
Anything ahead of us?
前方的情况怎么样
No signs of humans or monsters.
没有人也没有魔物
Even if we get attacked,
就算有魔物来袭击
you can turn into a dragon and finish them off easily.
只要你变成龙解决它们就行了
You know, that technique is very exhausting.
老实说 那招很累人
It depletes a lot of mana.
消耗庞大的魔力
My hips and legs will be sore the next day.
隔天腰和腿会觉得很累
The others get it, right?
你们懂吧
Yeah.
这样啊
It's very tiring to use magic.
使用魔法真的很辛苦
Hold on, are they...
难道这些家伙…
Muscle brain!
脑袋装肌肉
Incompetent!
无能
Basement dweller!
就只是个家里蹲
I wish I could go home now.
我突然好想回家
Come on...
别这样嘛
There is a place not far ahead where we can take a break.
往上走一点 有能休息的地方
We'll spend the night there.
今天只能先在那落脚了
All right. Come on, youngsters!
好了 加油 年轻人
We can take a break pretty soon!
马上就能休息了
Fine...
好
Well, Gramps, you're the Great Sage.
那个 爷爷你是大贤者吧
Can you be honest with me?
请你告诉我
Is there any meaning to collecting the rings?
收集戒指真的有意义吗
Why do you ask?
为什么突然问这个
The empire is planning to fight the Abyss King
帝国的人们打算不靠戒指的力量
without the power of the rings.
与深渊王抗衡吧
They eliminated almost all the monsters
实际上 袭击麻萨的魔物
that attacked Maasa.
也几乎被他们消灭了
It all seems different from what I had expected.
总觉得跟我想的有点不同
A hero who saved the world...
拯救世界的勇者
The legendary Ring King who defeated the Abyss King...
打倒深渊王的传奇戒王
It sounds great on the surface,
表面上是这么说
but people don't really expect anything from me.
事实上大家并不觉得期待吧
You could be right.
也许吧
It's a big world.
世界很宽广
Different people live their lives with different ideals.
不同的人怀着不同想法度日
Not everyone shares the same hope.
并不是所有人都仰赖同样的希望
If the humans can defeat monsters without any help,
如果人类能自己打倒魔物
they can probably defeat the Abyss King, too.
应该也能打倒深渊王
It's perfectly reasonable to think that way.
会这么想也合情合理
Is that so?
是吗
These rings are not as trusted by the people
这些戒指比我想象中
as I thought.
还要不被信任呢
However,
但是
I've seen my fair share of the world
我活到这个岁数
at this point.
见过各种各样的事
There were bits and pieces,
虽然只有片段
but I've heard horrible stories about the Abyss King,
但我听过许多深渊王的可怕传闻
including the scars that have endured since the mythic age.
包括从神话时代 流传至今的那些伤痛
There is no telling how powerful the Abyss King is.
深渊王的力量深不可测
We've seen it ourselves.
实际上我们也亲眼见过
He uses terrifying powers we can't undo with magic
他用连我们的魔术都解不开的
to control his knights and monsters.
可怕力量操控骑士和魔物
That power was only a small portion that leaked from his imprisonment.
而那只不过是从封印 漏出的些许力量
The humans will stand no chance against him without help.
光靠人类的力量根本束手无策
All the remaining records in this world
这个世界留下的所有纪录
led me to that conclusion.
都促使我这么想
Relax.
没事的
If the Abyss King comes back to life just as the legend says,
如果深渊王按照传说所述复活
so will the Ring King.
戒王也注定会复活
Satou, you've collected four rings.
佐藤你已经收集到四只戒指
The final one might present itself to you later on.
剩下的那只说不定会自己找上门
All right. My turn to keep watch.
好了 换我来守夜
Go and get some sleep.
你快去睡吧
All right.
好
How can I even call myself the Great Sage?
我算什么大贤者啊
I'm a failure.
真没用
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物语》
This is the Kingdom of Earth, Idanokan.
这就是土之国伊达诺坎
The fallen dwarven city.
没落的矮人族都城
Everything is in ruin.
真是残破不堪
They fended off the Abyss King's army several times.
他们好几次击退深渊王的进攻
But the final battle seemed pretty brutal.
但最后一战好像非常惨烈
Before they could even rebuild their city,
还没重建荒废的城市
the dwarves were gone.
矮人族就消失了啊
This place really seems empty.
好像真的没半个人
This silence is sending chills down my spine.
太安静了 让人有点发毛
Really? I'm quite fond of it.
会吗 我很喜欢哦
It's great to have the place to myself.
没有人真棒
I'd love to live here.
好想住在这里
It'd be even better if it were warmer.
要是能弄暖一点就好了
I'll wait here.
妾身在这里等
You can go on and look for the Ring of Earth yourself.
你们自己去找土之戒吧
What's wrong, Princess Saphir? Already worn out?
怎么了 瑟菲珞公主已经累了吗
I hate wandering aimlessly.
我讨厌像无头苍蝇一样到处乱走
This place is not far from the Abyss' domain.
这里很接近深渊的领域
I won't help if you get in trouble.
要是发生什么事 我可不管你
Well, then. Keep me out of trouble.
那你负责保护我不就好了
It's a great honour. Give it your best.
这可是荣幸 好好努力
You are unbelievable.
受不了 真拿你没办法
I'll carry you on my back.
我来背你
Come on. Get up.
好了 快上来
Huh?
什么
Nope! I can walk on my own.
不需要 我自己走
There is no need to be concerned, shy little girl.
不用客气啦 害羞鬼
I'm not!
我才没客气
Is that so?
是吗 是吗
What is it?
怎么了吗
I think someone's here.
好像有人在
Perhaps you got too edgy
可能是因为废墟太荒凉
from this desolation.
让你多心了吧
I see...
是吗
This place looks very clean.
这里倒是还满干净的
This looks like a throne.
还有类似王座的东西
The place was probably their palace.
这里应该就是王宫吧
And this is...
这是…
Gramps! There is a corpse here!
爷爷 有具尸体
Calm down, Satou.
冷静点 佐藤
That is not the body of a dwarf.
这不是矮人的尸体
It's an automaton, a relic of the mythic era.
是魔动士兵 神话时代的遗物
An automaton?
魔动…士兵
Like a robot?
是机器人吗
Relax.
放心吧
It won't move without mana.
没有魔力 它就不会动
This is nothing but a doll.
只是一具人偶
The dwarven civilisation was based around automation
矮人族的文明是魔动机关
and contraptions driven by mana.
以及用魔素驱动机械装置
They dig into the earth and forge metal parts.
挖掘大地 锻造金属
It was said that they would sacrifice their lives
据说他们为了磨练工匠的技艺
just to be the best craftsmen.
赌上了所有人生
This is the evidence of their existence and their technology.
这是他们活过的证明 也是技术成果
Back in the war during the mythical era,
在神话时代的战争
dwarves had already started using automatons as weapons.
矮人族就已经把魔动机关 作为兵器使用
The moving platform of Needakitta
尼妲齐达的魔动车
is one of the very few remaining relics.
也是少数还存在的遗物之一
I heard our ancestors got it from the dwarves long ago.
听说那是很早以前 祖先从土之国人民那里得到的
I had no idea
他们到底是怎么让它移动的
how the vehicle was moved.
我完全不知道
They left us all kinds of things to discover,
明明留下各种各样的东西
but no one knows what happened to them.
却没人知道最重要的矮人族 后来怎么了吗
It truly was a chaotic time.
看来那个时代真的很混乱呢
As I expected, there is nothing here to help us locate the ring.
果然 即使来到这里 也找不到有关戒指的线索啊
Should we check the underground tunnel?
只能去地下坑道看看了吗
Underground? We have to keeping going?
地下? 还要继续走吗
Perished...
消失了
We perished...
我们消失了
Everyone in the Kingdom of Earth...
土之国人民 全都…
Gramps, what is going on here?
喂 爷爷 这是怎么回事
Looks like things could still be functional.
还有东西会动吗
But how?
这怎么可能
Wait, this is...
不 这是…
The Abyss King's knight!
深渊王的骑士吗
He can control even machines?
居然连机械都能支配
He never ceases to surprise.
真是无奇不有啊
Why?
为什么
We fought on the same side.
我们和你们一同奋战
But why were we the ones who perished?
但是为什么只有我们消失
Why did we have to die?
为什么只有我们必须灭亡
What is it talking about?
它在说什么
Wind, Fire, Water, and Light... All of them shall perish!
风 火 水 光也一起灭亡吧
You will be sent to where we are,
跟我们的主人…
together with our lord!
和我们一起去同样的地方
The Abyss will devour you!
被深渊吞没吧
Oh no!
糟了
Satou is trapped on the other side.
佐藤在墙的另一头
What is going on now?
怎么回事
Don't get in my way, boy from another world.
别妨碍我 异界的人
The fate of this world doesn't concern you.
你和这个世界没有任何关系
You have no reason to fight for it.
也没有理由为它而战
No, you are wrong.
不 我有
I may not come from this world,
我的确不是这个世界的人
but this world
但是
has people who live in peace
这个世界有安稳生活的人们
and all of Hime's loved ones.
还有小姬所爱的人们
Are they worth risking your life for?
这些事值得你赌上性命吗
Yes.
值得
I want to protect Hime's world.
我想守护小姬的世界
I will defend it!
我一定要守护
Satou!
佐藤
Thanks, Hime.
谢谢你 小姬
You fool.
愚蠢的家伙
You are being used by the people.
你只是被这个世界利用了
Do the dwarves hate us?
矮人族他们憎恨我们吗
Who knows?
不知道
Maybe it said that
可能是受到深渊王的黑暗影响
under the influence of the Abyss King.
才会说那些话吧
It's time.
时候到了
It's for the resurrection.
复活的时刻到了
The ancient king shall come back to life!
古老的王即将复活
What now?
怎么回事
The black ring is vanishing.
黑色的戒指消失了
What?
什么
All the black rings
黑色的戒指…
are vanishing.
消失了
Finally...
终于…
It has begun.
开始了吗
What is happening?
发生…什么事
Watch out! Brace yourself!
小心点 要来了
Abyssal Creatures!
深渊的魔物
It's too risky to start fighting until we know more.
还没搞清楚状况就打起来很危险
Let's get out of here.
我们先出去吧
There are hordes of them.
居然有这么多
Where are they coming from?
到底是从哪里冒出来的啊
Were they summoned here?
是被某人召唤出来的吗
But there are too many of them.
数量也太多了
In that case...
既然这样
Master! We need your help!
大师 麻烦你了
My help?
妾身吗
Turn into a dragon and fend them off!
你用变成龙那招击退它们吧
No, I can't do it.
不行 我办不到
The transformation requires a lot of mana.
那种力量庞大的招式
I can't use it on a land with so little water-element mana.
在水的魔素稀少的这块土地用不了
Are you kidding me?
不会吧
Satou.
佐藤
Get ready for combat.
准备迎敌吧
Satou! Behind you!
佐藤 小心后面
I'll cover you.
我负责掩护你
Thanks.
得救了
Gramps, how did this happen?
喂 爷爷 怎么会这样
They just keep coming.
简直没完没了
There's no end to this. There is no other way.
打不完吗 没办法了
Run! This way!
快跑 往这边走
We must get away now!
趁现在拉开距离
Are you all right?
你没事吧
I'm all right.
我没事
Just a bit exhausted. All I need is a break.
这点疲劳 休息一下就没事了
This is bad. His stamina depletes too quickly.
不妙啊 体力消耗太剧烈了
At this rate...
这样下去的话…
Unbelievable!
真是不敢相信
There should have been more time.
应该还有一点时间的
No. I should've known better.
不 是我想得太美了
We are doomed!
没救了
What... What is going on now?
这是…什么情况
The Abyss King has been fully resurrected!
深渊王彻底复活了
The number of monsters...
那些魔物的数量…
Without all five rings,
没有五只戒指
the Ring King can't unleash his true power.
戒王就得不到真正的力量
Battling the monsters will be futile.
即使战斗也没有胜算
Would the Ring King collect all five rings first?
究竟是戒王会先取得五只戒指
Would the Abyss King come back to life before that?
还是深渊王会先复活
It was a gamble with this world.
我和这个世界
And I lost.
在这场赌注中输掉了
Satou...
佐藤
Our priority now is to flee.
总之我们得快逃
We have to find the Ring of Earth.
去寻找土之戒
There could still be time.
又还没有确定为时已晚了
He won't let us escape so easily.
他不会轻易让我们逃走的
No. The Abyss King will hunt us down to the edge of the world.
不 就算逃到天涯海角都没用
He will find us.
深渊王一定会找到我们
No! What should we do now?
不会吧 那我们该怎么办
Don't worry.
放心吧
I won't let him take your lives.
我不会眼睁睁看着他杀掉你们
Gramps, what are you doing?
爷爷 你要做什么
Opening a portal.
打开传送门
The Abyss King must never get his hands on the rings.
绝对不能让戒指落入深渊王手中
Gramps!
爷爷
Don't come here!
别过来
I can take it from here.
这里就交给我吧
By closing the portal,
只要把门关上
there is no way the Abyss King can pursue you.
深渊王再厉害也追不过去
In order for you to escape,
为了让你们逃走
I must stay to close the portal.
我必须留下来立刻关上门
If it remained open,
如果因为门开着
our plan could be ruined.
又打乱计划就伤脑筋了
Satou, you are my only hope.
佐藤 你是我的希望
Sorry we have to say our goodbyes this way.
很抱歉以这种方式跟你道别
Please free the princesses from their fate with the rings.
请你让公主们摆脱戒指的宿命吧
Take care of Hime.
姬乃就拜托你了
No!
不要
Gramps!
爷爷
Are you sure you want to stay?
你来我这边真的好吗
I've made up my mind
我已经下定决心
to defend this world until the very end.
要为这个世界奋战到最后一刻
Sorry for dragging you into this mess.
对不起 把你拖下水
No.
不会
It's a great honour to fight by your side,
如果是和大贤者一起
Great Sage.
我很荣幸
That's right.
对哦
I remember now.
我想起来了
It must feel worse for the others.
大家一定比我更痛苦吧
Gramps...
爷爷…
Are we really back?
我们真的回来了吗
This... This feels awful.
好…好难受
It doesn't fit well.
果然不行吗
What is this thing?
这是什么东西
It's a bra.
是胸罩
Try putting it on.
你穿穿看吧
Can I?
可以吗
I feel like I'm tied up.
有种被勒紧的感觉
This is incredible.
真不可思议
It kind of makes me nervous.
让人绷紧神经
Why would you wear something so fancy under the clothes?
在衣服下面穿这种花俏的东西
Isn't it pointless?
有意义吗
Your underwear is not meant to be shown to others.
内衣本来就不是穿给别人看的
But you do that all the time.
你不是总是露出来吗
Well... A little bit of that can work quite well.
那是因为稍微露一点 效果还不错
The answer to that is pretty obvious.
别问这种不知趣的事啦
I get it now. It's meant to seduce men.
我懂了 是为了引诱男人吧
What...
什…
Hime?
小姬
A bra?
胸罩
Hey, bring me the size that fits me.
喂 快拿出妾身能穿的尺寸
I don't have anything like that.
我怎么可能有啊
This shirt smells funny.
这件衣服有奇怪的味道
That belonged to Gramps!
那件是爷爷的
Princess Krystal!
克莉丝朵殿下
What is "free shipping?"
免运费是什么意思
Satou. Good... Good morning.
佐藤 早…早安